

Lyubomir Ganev

E-mail: luboganev@gmail.com **Website:** https://luboganev.dev

About me

I am a software engineer focused on native Android development. Through the years I have worked also in other areas of the software development like desktop applications and backend and frontend web development. I am curious and enjoy learning and trying out new technologies while doing some programming during my free time.

Personal Skills & Competences

Software Technologies

Programming Languages: Kotlin, Java, Swift.

Frameworks: Android SDK, Bluetooth, BLE, Gradle, Firebase, Fabric, Crashlytics, Answers, Google Analytics, Play Services, HockeyApp / AppCenter.

Libraries: Coroutines, Support Library, Architecture Components, Jetpack, Picasso, Lottie, Butterknife, RxJava 1 & 2, RxAndroid, Arrow, Koin, Dagger 1 & 2, Retrofit 1 & 2, Timber, OkHttp, Gson, Parceler, Realm, JUnit, Mockito, Roboelectric, Espresso.

Web Technologies: HTTP, REST, XML, JSON, HTML, CSS, Regex, REST, Markdown, Jekyll.

Version Controlling: Git, Git Flow, GitHub, Gitlab, Bitbucket, Stash, SVN.

Continuous Integration: Jenkins, TeamCity.

Databases Technologies: Room, Realm, MySQL, SQLite.

Operating Systems: Mac OS, Android, Windows, Linux.

Programming Environments: Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, IntelliJ Idea, XCode, Brackets, Atom.

Other Competences: Clean, VIPER, MVP, MVVM, Reactive programming, Functional programming, Open Source, Code Reviews, Pair Programming, Stack Overflow, Slack, Skype, Scrum, Kanban, Agile, JIRA, Confluence.

Languages

Bulgarian - Native language

English - Fluent (Level C1).

German - Fluent (Level C1).

Work Experience

Mar	201	9 -	present
-----	-----	-----	---------

ThinxNet GmbH

Munich, Germany

Senior Android developer

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps in the smart connected automobiles area.

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

Luxoft GmbH

Munich, Germany

Technical Lead Android

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps in the automotive environment.

Sep 2016 - Aug 2018

Bragi GmbH

Munich, Germany

Technical Lead Android

Architecture, implementation, QA and maintenance of native Android Apps, in-house prototypes and SDK for third parties.

July 2014 - Aug 2016

Jochen Schweizer Technology Solutions GmbH

Munich, Germany

Mobile Developer

Development of native Android and iOS Apps.

Dec 2013 - June 2014

CHIP Digital GmbH

Munich, Germany

Android Developer

Development of native Android and iOS Apps and REST Back-End.

May 2012 - Nov 2013

1st Position GmbH

Saarbrücken, Germany

Android Developer

Development of native Android Apps and REST Back-End.

Mar 2011 - Dec 2011

Institut für Wirtschaftsinformatik (IWI) bei DFKI GmbH

Saarbrücken, Germany

Research assistant

Development of back-end functionality and the front-end mobile user interface part

of the uService project. (http://uservices.de/)

Dec 2008 - Oct 2009

Mobiltel EAD

Sofia, Bulgaria

Web developer

Internal and external company web sites and web applications.

Education

Oct 2009 - Mar 2012

Saarland University

Saarbrücken, Germany

MSc Computer Science

Subjects covered: Database systems, Cryptography, Security, Mobile applications development, Innovative Technologies in Retail Environment, Multi-touch interactions, User interface design and usability

Master Thesis Topic: Framework for Evaluation of Recommender Systems that Suggest Mobile Applications

Oct 2004 - May 2008

Technical University - Sofia

Sofia, Bulgaria

BSc Computer Science

Subjects covered: OOP, Computer networks, Operating systems, Discrete structures, Algorithms synthesis, Computer graphics

References

Publications

AppFunnel: a framework for usage-centric evaluation of recommender systems that suggest mobile applications

Matthias Böhmer, Lyubomir Ganev, Antonio Krüger IUI '13

AppDetox: helping users with mobile app addiction

Lyubomir Ganev, Matthias Böhmer, Markus Löchtefeld MUM '13

Projects

AppDetox

Android application

AppDetox was developed by the AppDocs team which consists of three researchers/developers including myself. The purpose of the app is to provide heavy Android users with a tool that helps them perform self-control and tame their mobile apps usage on daily basis. Further information available on the official application

page in Google Play.

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=de.dfki.appdetox)

Anidro

Android application

Anidro is a fun app which brings motion to static drawings. Users can create simple drawings on their smartphone or tablet and then share an animated version of these drawings as an animated GIF or video. It is an open-source project which highlights some architectural best practices. Further information available on the official application page in Google Play and the GitHub page of the project.

(https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=app.anidro) (http://luboganev.dev/anidro/)

Further projects

For more projects please visit my website.

(https://luboganev.dev/about/)